Finding Aid for Minto-Skelton Papers
William L. Clements Library, University of Michigan
- II: Walter Minto Skelton (1804-48) and Family
  - 4. Documents (probate, land, certificates, summons, etc.)
    - Detargny, Cf. section I.A above, letters of Gamble, Garcia del Rio, and Hopkins. (Box 4, Folder 21)
      - 30 April 1797, Summons to [Marin] Detargny for guard duty, Paris, 11 Floreal, l'an cinquieme
      - 26 May 1797, Summons to [Marin] Detargny for guard duty, Paris, 7 Prairial, l'an cinquieme (formerly in 1934 Minto donation)
      - 18 April 1798, Carte de Surete for Marin Detargny, Bureau Central, Canton de Bordeaux, 29 Germinal, l'an sixieme (M.D., profession = Professeur, has lived in Bordeaux for 1 year)
      - 13 June 1798, Birth certificate for Marin Detargny, born 26 June 1776 son of Jean Francois Detargny, Archives du Departement de la Seine, Commune de Paris, 24 Prairial, l'an 6e (formerly in 1934 Minto donation)
      - 13 June 1798, Copy of death certificate for Jean Francois Detargny, died 26 March 1794 aged 60 years of age, Commune de Paris, 24 Prairial, l'an 6 (formerly in 1934 Minto donation)
      - 20 October 1798, Certificat de Conscription for Marin Detargny, "homme de lettres," Canton de Bordeaux, 29 Vendemiaire, septieme annee (formerly in 1934 Minto donation)
      - 22 November 1798, Carte de Surete for Marin Detargny, "homme de lettres," Bureau Central, Canton de Marseille (M.D. has been living in Marseille for [?less than] 3 months), le Deux frimaire, an 7e (formerly in 1934 Minto donation)
      - 28 April 1804, Statement signed by six citizens of Annapolis certifying that Mr. Marin Detargny has resided in said city as a French teacher for 17 months and "has behaved himself with propriety, and sustained the Character of a Gentleman"
      - 1805, One sheet of paper, folded (addressed on outside to Rev. Mr. Detargny). 11 November 1805 Resolution (on page 1) from the Council Chamber, Charleston, that 29 November be set apart as a day of General Thanksgiving to God for all the benefits and blessings conferred on the citizens of said city and that the clergy of the city be requested to promote this to their congregations on that day.12 November 1805 Circular (on page 2) from the Intendant, Charleston, conveying this request.
      - 1 December 1806, Receipt from the Reverend Marin Detargny, Charleston, for $12.75 "as a Consideration" for a "Policy of Assurance" for $2000 to be issued by Phoenix Assurance-Company of London, signed by Jno. M. Davis, Agent
      - 18 August 1807, Authorization from Charles Lining, "Esquire, Ordinary," South Carolina, Charleston District, to the Reverend Mr. Marin Detargny to join in matrimony Joseph Finch of Charleston, Manufacturer of Cut Nails, and Catharine Spencer of Charleston, Spinster
    - Franklin Heirs (Box 4, Folder 22)
      - 9 June 1785, Survey by Joshua Elder of a plot of land called "Settle," containing 200 4/10 acres, in Westmoreland County, Pennsylvania, for Benjamin Franklin; returned to secretary's office for Benjamin Franklin 10 October 1787
      - 29 October 1814, Deed of sale of 11 tracts of land on the northwest side of the Allegheny River, "now or formerly" in Westmoreland County, by Louis Bache and Richard Bache, executors of the will of Richard Bache, deceased, of Settle, Bucks County, Pennsylvania, acting on behalf of some of the members of the Bache family in Pennsylvania, heirs of Benjamin Franklin, and by other members of the family in their own right, to Randall Hutchinson; recorded in Armstrong County 21 August 1815
      - 29 October 1814, Deed of sale of the tract called "Settle," "now or formerly" in Westmoreland County, from Randall Hutchinson to William I. Duane and his wife Deborah (who are one of the parties to the sale of the 11 tracts in previous item) for $1.00; recorded in Armstrong County 21 August 1815
      - 24 January 1840, Deed of sale of a tract of land called "Settle" (of 200 4/10 acres), formerly in Westmoreland County but now in Armstrong, by William I. Duane and Deborah his wife to WMS for $4000
      - 24 January 1840, Deed of sale of a tract of land called "Broughton" (of 209 7/10 acres), formerly in Westmoreland County but now in Armstrong, by William I. Duane and Deborah his wife to WMS for $4180
    - McFarland (Box 4, Folder 23)
      - Undated, ca. 1887, Draft claim of Hannah P. Boyd and Mary McFarland, sisters of George McFarland, for "arrears of pay and bounty.", On a form that has 188 plus a blank for the year in the decade (probably 1887). George, a private in Company G, 5th Regiment of the "Calafornia Volunteers," died "on or about the" 31st October 1862 in the service of the U.S.; the sisters appoint Calvin Rayburn of Kittanning to prosecute the claim (see letter of Rayburn to Hannah Boyd above in section I.C)
      - 1 June 1908, Bill for funeral expenses of $66.79 for Mrs. [sic; cf. previous item] Mary S. McFarland from S. Turner and Son, Freeport., With receipt of payment by Miss Lizzie Boyd dated 8 December 1908. Since the actual expenses are dated 6 August 1904 this may have been a second or third bill.
    - Scudder (Box 4, Folder 24)
      - 13 March 1826, Deed of sale of land by Jacob Scudder and his wife Hester to William Gulick in Montgomery Township, Somerset County, New Jersey., Jacob Scudder, May have been the son of H[annah] S[cudder]: see her letter to her husband in section I.A above.
    - Skelton Family
      - Ann Skelton (1818-1906) (Box 4, Folder 25)
        - 13 June 1856, Survey ("Draft") of a tract of land (i.e., the 2 tracts mentioned in Walter Skelton, item 3) for Ann Skelton (cf. WMS.'s wills in Walter Skelton, items 2 and 4)
        - 11 May 1858, Indenture by Jacob M. Bush to Ann Skelton., For $1100 with interest, to be paid according to a schedule ending in 1862 for 25+ acres of land, part of a larger tract conveyed by William I. Duane to Walter Skelton (either item 4 or 5 in Franklin heirs or both), who devised it to Ann Skelton, Sarah Skelton, and Joseph Skelton Jr. (see Walter Skelton, item 4), and Joseph Skelton Jr. and his wife Elizabeth conveyed 184 acres of which this is a part to Ann Skelton.
        - 22 July 1900, Lease by Ann Skelton of Freeport Borough, Armstrong County, to Thomas McCauley and P.J. McCauley of Pittsburgh., Leases the right to quarry stone on the southern part of a piece of land owned by her for a period of 5 years initially, with the possibility of a further 5 years; the McCauleys to pay her rental of 10 cents per cubic yard and to quarry at least 2000 cubic yards each year.
        - 29 November 1904, Grant by Ann Skelton to the Kiskiminetas Connecting Railroad Co., For a right of way 66 feet wide for the location, etc. of a railroad over 10 acres more or less of her land in South Buffaloe Township, Armstrong County, for $50; sealed and delivered in the presence of W.M. Boyd.
        - Undated, Informal draft of someone's will (probably Ann Skelton's)., Leaving specific items of her personal property to Hannah Boyd, Lizzie Boyd, John H. Boyd, and Helen M. McIntyre and, after expenses have been paid, dividing the profits from the remainder of her personal property and from her real estate equally to the same four persons (except that Helen McIntyre's part is to be shared with her brother Charles B. McIntyre).; Dates to before 4 February 1911 (Boyd, item 4) because W.M. Boyd is referred to as still alive, but not clear how much earlier; before 30 March 1906 and certainly before 1 July 1906 (see next item), if Ann Skelton is the writer.
        - 1 July 1906, Bill and receipt for funeral expenses of $116.75 for Miss Ann Skelton from S. Turner and Son, Freeport, Paid by Lizzie Boyd, Executrix (probably dead by 30 March 1906 see letter of Duffy to Hill above in section I.B).
        - Undated, ca. 1933-1934, Notification by County Treasurer, Kittanning, to estate of Annie Skelton., Her property in South Buffalo has been returned for non-payment of taxes for 1932 amounting to $12.81 and, unless they are paid, the property will be sold at the Court House in Armstrong County on 6 August 1934.
      - Elizabeth Skelton (?-1826) (Box 4, Folder 26)
        - 29 March 1825, Will of Elizabeth Skelton., Leaving all of her personal property and real estate to her nephew WMS, except for some plate and wearing apparel (to Elizabeth McFarland, niece, daughter of Joseph and Sarah Skelton) and a mourning ring (to Harriet Nicholson, niece, daughter of Samuel and Hannah Nicholson); appoints John Lowrey executor, unless WMS is of legal age at time of her death, in which case he is to be executor; certified as true copy 13 November 1826 Elizabeth Skelton now deceased.
        - 29 March 1825, Copy of preceding item; certified as such 17 June 1839
        - 13 November 1826, Inventory of possessions of Elizabeth Skelton; certified 18 November 1829 Elizabeth Skelton now deceased
      - Joseph Skelton Sr. (?-before 1840) (Box 4, Folder 27)
        - Undated, marriage certificate., Certificate by Thomas Lyell, witnessed by W. [?]. Bessonett and James Thorburn: "This will certify that I did on Thursday evening the 27 of May join together in marriage Mr. Joseph Skelton and Miss Sarah White."; Probably before 1803, when the Skeltons' 1st child was born.
      - Mary Skelton Minto (?-1824)
        - 9 November 1796, Receipt by Enos Kelley to Mary Minto for the items mentioned in document B.16 (a) in Series 1: IV.Documents (this receipt is now item B.16 (b) in Series 1: IV.Documents)
        - 1796 [day and month torn away]: Codicil by Mary Skelton [Minto], executrix of Minto's last will (he being deceased), to a bond of indemnity (dated 28 September 1795) by Minto to Richard Stockton for 1180 pounds, probably asking to have debt set aside (this is now item B.10 (b) in Series 1: IV.Documents)
        - 23 May 1801, Bill of lading for one box, shipped from Leith to New York on the Russell, directed to Mrs. Minto, to be delivered to Mrs. Chrystie of New York for payment; contents unknown to Rowland Gibbs, master of the Russell (this is now item B.17 in Series 1: IV.Documents)
        - 25 August 1812, Middlesex County, State of New Jersey: Certificate that Mary Minto brought before 2 overseers of the poor and 2 justices of the peace her female slave named Gitty, who appears to be of sound mind and not under any bodily incapacity, between 21 and 40 years; recorded in Clerk's office, no date (Box 4, Folder 28)
        - 25 August 1812, Statement of Mary Minto that she has set free her slave Gitty (of 21 years or thereabouts); recorded in Clerk's office on 26 August 1812
        - 8 January 1817, Will of Mary Minto, leaving $100 to her sister Sarah Clark, $600 to Walter Minto Skelton (to be used at the discretion of her sister Elizabeth), and the remainder of her personal property and all of her real estate to her sister Elizabeth; appoints her sister executrix and administratrix; certified as a true copy of the will by a surrogate in New Brunswick on 17 June 1839
      - Walter Skelton (1804-48) (Box 4, Folder 29)
        - 20 October 1830, Commission of Walter M. Skelton to be Captain of the company Princeton Blues, having been elected to such position on 25 May 1830
        - ca. 1840, Draft of will of WMS, leaving to his mother, Sarah Skelton, "a comfortable maintenance" out of his estate, and then leaving everything to his sister Ann Skelton; appoints Ann executrix
        - 21 April 1841, Survey of 2 tracts of land in Buffaloe Township, Armstrong County, for WMS (these are the tracts sold to him in 1840 mentioned in Franklin heirs, items 4 and 5 above)
        - 16 September 1845, Will (copy) of WMS, of Buffaloe Township, Armstrong County; leaving 1/3 to his sister Ann Skelton, 1/3 to his brother Joseph Skelton, Jr., and 1/3 in trust to his sister Ann for the use of his mother Sarah Skelton; appoints Ann executrix; will proved in Kittanning, Pennsylvania 20 June 1848 (Walter Skelton being deceased), and certified in Register's Office 21 June 1848
    - White (Box 4, Folder 30)
      - 23 March 1839, Will of Elizabeth White of Scarsdale, Westchester County, New York, leaving the bulk of her estate to (1) various charities (half) and (2) her 3 sisters, Mary Bessonett, Phebe White, and Jane White (half, in various proportions); certified as true copy 12 October 1841 Elizabeth White now deceased
      - 13 June 1839, Memorandum of land owned by Elizabeth White in Illinois, deeded to her on 1 April 1837 and recorded in Illinois on 27 June 1837
  - 5: Printed Materials
    - 31 December 1799, Sacred music, to be performed in St. Paul's Church, on Tuesday the 31st December, 1799 by the Anacreontic and Philharmonic Societies, at the Funeral Ceremonies in honor of the Memory of the late General Washington [New York, 1799]. (formerly in 1934 Minto donation)
    - ca. early 1800s, "Boarding and Education for Young Ladies, At Mrs GRAHAM's, Broadway, NEW YORK": advertisement and list of fees (on a ca. 3" x 5" card) for a school run by Isabella Graham (1742-1814); Mrs. Graham began teaching in New York in late 1789 when fees for schools like hers were ca. $80 per year for full boarders; by the time of this advertisement her fee was $125 for full boarders, which must put the date considerably later than 1789 Mrs. Graham was a good friend of the Mrs. Chrystie who corresponded with the Mintos from the 1790s until 1810 and who is often mentioned in other correspondence, along with her husband, Major (later Colonel) Chrystie. (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - 29 August 1844 The Clay Bugle, No. 35, Harrisburg, Thursday, [Pa.,] August 29, 1844 a weekly Whig campaign newspaper created to support the candidacy of Henry Clay for President of the U.S. (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - 13 March 1852, The Home Journal, for the week ending Saturday March 13, 1852 ed. George Pope Morris and Nathaniel Parker Willis, "[Whole NO. 318.--SERIES FOR 1852--NO. 11." [New York]. (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - 1882, Proceedings of the First Boyd Convention Held at Beaver, Pennsylvania, October 26 and 27, 1881. Published by the Boyd Association Historical Committee. Youngstown, Ohio: Youngstown Publishing Company, 1882. 42 pages. (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - ca. early 1883, The Second Re-Union of the Descendants of John and Mary-Fulton Boyd, will be held in Lima, Allen County, Wednesday and Thursday, October 24th and 25th, 1883. Printed in Chambersburg, Pa., [?early 1883]. Announcement of reunion, with program, committees, etc.; 1 leaf folded in half to make 4 pages, the last of which is blank. (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - 7. 1884, Proceedings of the Second Boyd Convention Held at Lima, Ohio, October 24th and 25th, 1883. Youngstown, Ohio: W.H. Woodrow, 1884. 48 pages.
    - 1885, Proceedings of the Third Boyd Convention Held at Kiskiminetas Springs, Saltsburg, Pa., August 27th and 28th, 1884. Youngstown, Ohio: W.H.Woodrow, 1885. 33 pages. (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - ca. early 1887, Call for a Reunion to Be Held at Slate Lick, Pennsylvania, Tuesday and Wednesday, August 30 and 31, 1887. Announcement to residents and former residents of Slate Lick; 1 leaf folded in half to make 4 pages, the last of which is blank; addressed to Miss A. Skelton at Scilney, Pa. [postmarked "Kittanning"]. (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - 1887, Re-Union at Slate Lick, Pa. Of Present and Former Residents, Tuesday and Wednesday, August 30 & 31, 1887. "Programme" of events. 1 narrow leaf, with printing on recto only.
    - 1888, Proceedings of the Fourth Boyd Convention Held at Hamilton, Ohio, September 15th and 16th, 1886. H. Byxbe, 1888. 26 pages. (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - 1888, Proceedings of the Fifth Boyd Convention Held at Pittsburgh, Pa., (Hotel Boyer,) September 5th and 6th, 1888. H. Byxbe, 1888. 59 pages. (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - 1892, Proceedings of the Sixth Boyd Convention Held at Marion, Ohio, (Hotel Marion,) August 27th and 28th, 1890. H. Byxbe, 1892. 42 pages. (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - 1894, Proceedings of the Seventh Boyd Convention Held at Seventh Avenue Hotel, Pittsburgh, Pa., August 31st and September 1st, 1892. H. Byxbe, 1894. 30 pages. (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - 3 newspaper clippings about family events: (Box 4, Folder 42)
      - [May 1935]: Article, perhaps from a newspaper in Tarentum, Pa. (since on the reverse is an advertisement for "Chantler's" in that city), about Amelia Earhart's non-stop flight from Mexico City to New York City on May 8; mentions Samuel (age 68) and Ida (age 73) Earhart, first cousins of Amelia's father Edwin Earhart (who was a schoolmaster near Saltsburg, Pa.), and another cousin, Emma Elizabeth Earhart Fleming (age 83) of Indiana, Pa.; Amelia's grandfather, Rev. David Earhart, had the Lutheran parsonage in Apollo, Pa., and the Earhart family used to visit Samuel and Ida.
      - [November 1949]: Death notice, probably from a Pittsburgh newspaper, of Frank F. McIntyre of Altoona, Pa., on 16 November 1949 Frank was the father of Charles B. McIntyre and Helen B. McIntyre of Pittsburgh; the funeral was held in Freeport, Pa.
      - 14 June 1956: Notice from the Pittsburgh Press of the honoring of Miss Helen McIntyre, retiring school teacher, by the Shakespeare School PTA in East Liberty, Pa.
  - 6: Notes, Invitations, Miscellanea
    - Notes (all in WMS's hand except the last two)
      - Syllabus, with required readings; probably from WMS's years at the College of New Jersey., Single leaf, with writing on recto only. (Box 5, Folder 1)
      - A list of college classes, beginning on a Tuesday and going to the following Monday, with only Sunday omitted; probably from WMS's years at the College of New Jersey., Scrap of paper, with writing on recto only.
      - A set of 5 series of surnames, followed by "Valedictory. D. Crawford": perhaps a list of College of New Jersey graduates or graduation speakers (WMS's name is not among them)., Half a leaf, with writing on recto only.
      - "Catalogue of Books," divided into "Classicks & French," "Class Books & Books of Science," "Novels & Plays," "Books of a miscellaneous kind," "Musick"; probably WMS's library, with catalogue written in what appears to be a formal variety of his hand., Large single leaf, folded in half vertically to make 4 pages.
      - "Provincialisms noticed in the Western part of Pennsylvania," a series of equivalents in the form "A for B," signed (on reverse) "Skelton," followed by WMS's height and weight measured in "Peal's Museum" on 8 February 1826 then signed again "W.M. Skelton.", Small single leaf.
      - Recipe "To boil a Fowl"; this leaf was found in item (a) (1818-[3]4) in section II.A.2, but it is not certain if it was there originally: the hand is quite different and appears to be untrained., Small single leaf, with writing on recto only. (Box 5, Folder 2)
      - "Kate's Manumission Papers," (at the top of the second quarter (from the left) of the recto), probably in a Skelton family hand (but earlier than the late family hands in section F below)., Scrap of rag paper ca. 11 1/2 " x 4 1/2 ", folded in 4 roughly equal parts and apparently used to enclose something.
    - Invitations
      Some on backs of playing cards, marked with * below.
      - 4 March 1780, [Princeton]*: to Miss Skelton from the Gentlemen of the College to a dance and a play (Box 5, Folder 3)
      - 6 April 1780, Princeton*: to Miss Betsy Skelton from the Gentlemen of the Senior Class to public exhibitions in the College Hall
      - 17 February 1781, Princeton*: to Miss Betsy Skelton from the Gentlemen of the College to public exhibitions in the College Hall
      - 24 June 1782, Philadelphia: to Miss B. Baynton from the Minister of France to an entertainment to celebrate the birth of the Dauphin
      - 1 December 1782, Princeton: to Miss Skelton from the managers of an unnamed organization to a dance
      - 17 February 1783, Princeton*: to Miss Skelton from the Junior Class of College to a play and other exercises in the College Hall
      - 14 April 1783, Trenton: to Miss Polly Skelton from the Governor and the Gentlemen of Trenton to a dance "in Celebration of Peace" at Mr. Cape's
      - 22 April 1783, Princeton: to Miss Betsy Skelton from the Gentlemen of Princeton and its Vicinity to a ball "in Celebration of Peace" at Mr. Beekman's
      - December 1785, [Princeton]: to Miss Eliza Skelton for the season of the Princeton Assembly
      - 30 April [probably mid-1780s], [Princeton]: to Miss E. Skelton from the Gentlemen of the College to public exhibitions in the College Hall (Box 5, Folder 4)
      - 30 April [probably mid-1780s], [Princeton]: to Miss Polly Skelton from the Gentlemen of the College to public exhibitions in the College Hall
      - 23 September [probably mid-1780s]*, Princeton: to Miss Skelton to a dance at Mr. [?] d[.. .]
      - [late December /early January] [probably mid-1780s], Bordentown*: to the Miss Skeltons to a ball on Twelfth Night, 6 January
      - Tuesday morning [probably mid-1780s], [Princeton]: to the Miss Skeltons from Dr. Beatty to a dance at his house "this evening" (with additional comments about Mrs. Deane expecting to see the Miss Skeltons at her house for tea, etc.)
      - Saturday morning [probably mid-1780s], [Princeton]: to Miss Betsey Skelton from the Senior Class to the public orations in the College Hall
      - 6 February 1826, Harrisburg: to Mr. [Walter] Skelton to a Cotillion Party at the house of Mr. John Shock, Harrisburg, on Tuesday next; with envelope addressed to Mr. Skelton (Box 5, Folder 6)
      - 8 February 1834, to Miss Ann Skelton to a "Birth-Night Ball" at Mr. M'Anulty's Hotel, Blairsville, on 21 February 1834
      - February 1843, to Mr. W.M. Skelton & Lady to a Cotillion Party at the house of Mr. Isreal Hill, Leechburg, on 17 February 1843
    - Statement to James Carnahan 1823-?25: Statement directed to Dr. [James] Carnahan [president of the College of New Jersey from May 1823 to 1854], from a meeting of college, signed by 75 persons (including WMS), deploring some outrageous act by an unknown person and expressing their support. (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Small Notebook, Undated [?1830-31]: Small notebook containing "By-Laws of ‘The Princeton Blues'," followed by signatures of, presumably, the 62 members of the Company (Skelton's is the 4th one on the list)., Skelton was commissioned Captain of the Company on 20 October 1830 and resigned his commission on 8 July 1831 (see section IV. Walter Skelton, item 1).; 29 leaves, unnumbered, covered with boards; title on leaf [3a]; text on leaves [3a]-[8b]; signatures on leaves [13b]-[15a]. Not in WMS's hand. (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Booklet of proverbs and common sayings, Undated: in English (on versos), with Spanish equivalents (on facing rectos), entitled (on page [8]) "A Collection of Proverbs & Common Saying" and (on page [1]) "una Colleccion de refranes y de dichos communes.", 2 leaves, folded in half to make 4 (8 pages), unnumbered; English text on pages [8], [2], [4], [6], Spanish on [1], [3], [5], [7]. Not in WMS's hand.
    - Various notes, undated [but mainly 20th century]. Late family (?and other) notes, in various hands, made about the Minto-Skelton papers before they were given to the Clements Library.
      - 5 leaves, in ink (mainly) and pencil, listing letters in the Minto part of the collection (mainly addressed to him), a bond, a bill, and a few books (Box 5, Folder 9)
      - 2 leaves in pencil, listing a few books and giving a summary of the Minto letters (Box 5, Folder 10)
      - 7 small leaves in pencil, with writing on both sides, listing family books published between 1745 and 1870 (Box 5, Folder 11)
      - 1 3" x 5" card in ink with some dates (Box 5, Folder 12)
      - 17 xeroxes of 32 envelopes that contained some of the Minto-Skelton Papers, with notes on the outsides about what they contained (the envelopes themselves have been discarded) (Box 5, Folder 13)